The pseudocode starts with, when the order button is clicked.
El pseudocódigo empieza cuando se pulsa el botón de orden .
This indicates that we should add our code in the submit order method.
Esto indica que debemos añadir el código en el método de confirmación.
Then, we need to get the checked state from the checkbox.
Después, necesitamos obtener el estado de la casilla.
In order to call any methods on a view, in the view hierarchy,
Para visualizar cualquier método en la jerarquía de vista,
we need to first find view by id.
hay que encontrar primero "ver por identidad".
The first thing I need to do is assign a view id to this check box view.
Hay que asignar un identificador a la vista de la casilla.
In android studio in activity main layout I'm going to find the check
En Android Studio, en el plano de actividad principal,
box layout view.
buscamos la vista del plano de casilla.
Since my cursors here it highlights this view in the preview.
Como mi cursor está aquí, me destaca esta vista en la previsualización.
Then I'm going to add a line to send a view ID to this view.
Después voy a añadir una línea para enviar un ID a esta vista.
Now in the Java code, I can refer to this view, and
Ahora en Java, puedo dirigirme a esta vista
then try to extract the state from it.
y tratar de extraer el estado.
Let's go into the main activity.
Vayamos a la actividad principal.
I'm going to put my code in the submit order method.
Voy a poner mi código en el método de confirmación de compra.
I know that I need to find the CheckBox Java object in the view hierarchy.
Sé que necesito encontrar el objeto de casilla en Java, en la jerarquía.
I start by creating a variable, whippedCreamCheckBox,
Empiezo creando una variable, la casilla "whippedCream",
with data type CheckBox.
con tipo de datos casilla.
Then I can call the findViewById method within that activity.
Después puedo incluir en esa actividad el método "findViewByld".
This will find a view based on the given ID.
Esto encontrará una vista basándose en el ID especificado.
I'm going to pass in the ID (R.id.whipped_cream_checkbox),
Voy a pasar como parámetro el ID (R.id.whipped_cream_checkbox),
which I just assigned in the other layout file.
que acabo de asignarle en el otro plano.
This gives me an error immediately because the required type is CheckBox,
Esto me da error inmediatamente porque lo que pide es una Checkbox,
because this is what the variable on the left-hand side is.
ya que esa es la variable del lado izquierdo.
However, the return value of this method is of type view.
Sin embargo, el valor de vuelta de este método de tipo View.
So, just like we learned earlier,
Así que como aprendimos antes,
we need to cast the return value of this method.
tenemos que recuperar el valor de retorno de este método.
I'm going to cast it to be a CheckBox object.
Voy a recuperarlo como objeto CheckBox.
The reason why I can cast it Is because CheckBox is a subclass of View.
La razón por la que puedo hacerlo es porque CheckBox es una subclase de View.
Okay, now I have the CheckBox Java object
OK, ahora tengo el objeto Java CheckBox
that represents the checkbox in the UI.
que representa el CheckBox en la UI.
In order to figure out whether the box is checked or
Para averiguar si la casilla está marcada o no,
not, I need to call a method on the object.
necesito incluir un método en el objeto.
You may not know which method to call on the CheckBox object.
Puede que no sepas de qué método se trata.
And that's perfectly fine.
Y es perfectamente normal.
So you can just Google search for it.
Así que puedes buscarlo en Google.
Search for CheckBox Android, and then click on the first link.
Busca "CheckBox Android" y haz click en el primer enlace.
And to reinforce what I mentioned earlier, checkbox is a subclass of view.
Insisto, CheckBox es una subclase de View.
There's other views in between, but
Hay otras vistas en medio, pero
ultimately it's still a subclass of view.
sigue siendo una subclase de View.
This class overview is kind of interesting because it has some
Esta visión general es interesante porque tiene
Java code here.
algo de código Java.
It has this line of code which we already have in our app,
Tiene esta línea de código que ya tenemos en nuestra app,
we're doing find view by id, given an id and then getting a check box item back.
usamos "encontrar vista por ID", y después obtenemos una casilla.
This next line is even more interesting.
La siguiente línea es incluso más interesante.
It says check box, which is the name of this variable, dot is checked.
Dice "CheckBox", que es el nombre de esta variable, ".isChecked".
This looks like a method call with no input arguments.
Esto se parece a un método sin argumentos de entrada.
This appears to be telling us whether the box is checked or not, and returning
Parece indicarnos si la casilla está marcada o no, y volver
a true or false value, but let's check the check boxes guide to be sure.
a un valor verdadero o falso, pero veamos la guía para asegurarnos.
Let's scroll through this We see some checkbox xml code,
Avancemos... vemos algo de código checkbox xml,
and some more Java code.
y más de Java.
This method looks like it's called when the checkbox is clicked.
Parece que este método es llamado cuando se marca la casilla.
This method name matches the method name specified in the xml.
El nombre de este método encaja con el especificado en xml.
I'm assuming that the view that is being passed in is the check box view.
Doy por hecho que la vista que acabamos de pasar es la de check box.
And, we cast it to CheckBox, and
Y lo convertimos a CheckBox
we also called IsChecked, and the return value is a boolean.
activamos IsChecked y el valor de retorno es booleano.
The comment also describes it further, it says is the view now checked?
El comentario lo describe, dice si la vista está marcada.
So I think this is exactly what we need.
Exactamente lo que necesitamos.
Let's try to use the method IsChecked.
Usemos el método IsChecked.
First we type the variable name of the CheckBox object.
Primero tecleamos el nombre de la variable del objeto CheckBox.
It's whippedCreamCheckBox.
Es whippedCreamCheckBox.
Then I add a dot to call a method on it.
Después añado un punto para llamar uno de sus métodos.
I can start typing isChecked, and it pops up here.
Tecleando isChecked ya salta.
So I can hit Enter to use this suggestion.
Así que pulso Enter para usar la sugerencia.
On the right hand side here, it says what the return value of this method is,
En la parte derecha dice qué valor de retorno tendremos,
and it says it returns a boolean.
y es un booleano.
So after I use this suggestion, I'm going to go to the left hand side of
Después de usar esta sugerencia voy al lado izquierdo
this method call and then I'm going to store this result in a boolean variable.
de esta llamada y después voy a almacenar el resultado en una variable booleana.
I'm going to call this boolean variable hasWhippedCream, then hit Enter.
Voy a llamar a esta variable booleana hasWhippedCream, despues pulso Enter.
To recap, we're calling a method on the whippedCreamCheckbox Java object, and
Recapitulando, hacemos una llamada al objeto Java whippedCreamCheckbox
the method is called isChecked.
y este método se llama isChecked.
This has a return value of a boolean and
Tiene el valor de retorno de un booleano
it's being stored on the left-hand side here.
y se almacena aquí en el lado izquierdo.
In this variable called hasWhippedCream.
En esta variable llamada hasWhippedCream.
This completes the first task.
Esto completa la primera tarea.
I also mentioned that you can log this variable so
También mencioné que puedes registrar esta variable
you could verify that you're on the right path.
para verificar que vas en la dirección correcta.
So, on the next line, I'm going to add a log message.
En la línea siguiente voy a añadir un mensaje de registro.
The first argument is a tag name.
El primer argumento es una categoría.
And I'm just going to use the name of our class, which is MainActivity.
Y voy a usar el nombre de la nuestra, que es MainActivity.
Then I'm going to put my own message.
Después voy a poner mi propio mensaje.
I'm going to say Has whipped cream.
Voy a poner Has Whipped Cream.
And then add in the boolean variable.
Y luego añadir la variable booleana.
By concatenating this string here with the boolean variable,
Conectando esta secuencia con la variable booleana,
it will turn this boolean value into a string as well.
convertirá el valor booleano en una cadena también.
So then the text will say has whipped cream true, or has whipped cream false.
Así el texto dirá "Has Whipped Cream verdadero" o "Has Whipped Cream falso".
Now let's run the app on our device, and
Ahora ejecutemos la app en nuestro dispositivo
check that this is actually printing out the right log message.
y comprobemos que muestra el mensaje de registro correcto.
I increased the size of the log window using this control here.
He aumentado el tamaño de la ventana de registro con este control.
Now when I click on the whipped cream check box and
Ahora cuando hago clic en la casilla de WhippedCream
then hit the order button, I'll expect to see a message down here that says,
y presiono el botón de compra, vendrá un mensaje que diga
has whipped cream true or false.
Has Whipped Cream verdadero o falso.
I'm going to scroll this over so that I can see the actual message.
Voy a ir avanzando para poder verlo.
Okay, let's see if this works.
Veamos si funciona.
I'm going to check this box and then hit order.
Voy a marcar esta casilla y después doy la orden.
Okay, I think a new message got printed out and it says Main Activity.
Un nuevo mensaje aparece y dice "main activity".
Has whipped cream: true.
Dice "WhippedCream: true".
That's correct because the checkbox is checked.
Es correcto porque la casilla está marcada.
If I uncheck this box and then hit the order button, I expect it to say false.
Si desmarco la casilla y doy la orden, dirá "falso".
And scroll to the right again, and it says has whipped cream: false.
Avanzo a la derecha de nuevo y dice "has whipped Cream: falso".
Okay, so it looks like our code is correct so far for
Parece que nuestro código es correcto hasta ahora,
finding the checkbox view, and then getting the check state out of it.
tras encontrar la vista y extraer el check state.
Now let's continue to the second task.
Continuemos ahora con la segunda tarea.
Okay, now we need to pass this boolean variable into the order summary method.
Necesitamos pasar esta variable booleana en el método de resumen de pedido.
If I want to pass another argument into the createOrderSummary method,
Si quiero pasar otro argumento al método de createOrderSummary,
I'll just add a comma here, and then pass the variable, hasWhippedCream.
añado una coma y paso la variable hasWhippedCream.
Immediately I get an error that says, It can't be applied to
Inmediatamente obtengo un error que indica que no puede ser aplicado
the method createOrderSummary, because that just expects an integer parameter.
porque se espera un parámetro de número entero.
So let's scroll down to where createOrderSummary is declared.
Avancemos hacia abajo donde se expone createOrderSummary.
Now I need to modify the method signature
Necesito modificar la firma de método
of the createOrderSummary method.
del método createOrderSummary.
Instead of taking in one input parameter, it needs to take in two.
En lugar de introducir un parámetro de entrada, necesita dos.
The data type should be a boolean, and I'm going to call it addwhippedCream.
El tipo de dato debería ser booleano, y voy a llamarlo addwhippedCream.
You can call the input parameter whatever name you want, but
Al parámetro de entrada puedes llamarlo como quieras,
I just want to show you that this name does not have to match this name here.
pero quiero mostrarte que no tiene por qué ser igual que este otro.
Since we modified the method's signature here, we have to update the Java dock as
Como hemos modificado la firma de método, tenemos que actualizar Java
well to specify what this input parameter is about.
también para especificar de qué trata este parámetro de entrada.
Okay, that completes the second task.
Esto completa la segunda tarea.
The third task is to change the order summary text to include whether or
La tercera es cambiar el texto del resumen de pedido para incluir
not the user wants whip cream.
si el usuario quiere whip cream o no.
Essentially that means we need to use this input parameter here
En esencia quiere decir que usamos este parámetro aquí
to modify our order summary message.
para modificar nuestro mensaje de orden de sumario.
In the screen shot the whip cream topping line appeared below the name.
En la captura, la línea superior de whip cream sale bajo el nombre.
So let's add a new line here.
Así que hay que añadir una nueva línea aquí.
I'm going to type out price message plus equals
Voy a escribir "priceMessage +="
to modify the existing price message.
para modificar el mensaje de precio previo.
And then add the line Add whipped cream?
Y después añadir la línea addWhippedCream.
I'm going to add a space, and then add the boolean variable.
Voy a añadir un espacio, y después la variable booleana.
Again, I can catonate a string literal with a boolean value,
De nuevo, puedo enlazar una cadena con un valor booleano
and this will turn this whole thing into a string.
y esto transformará todo en una cadena.
Cool, now let's try it on our device.
Bien, ahora en nuestro dispositivo.
If I click on this check box and
Si marco la casilla
then click on the order button it should say add whip cream topping true.
y después hago clic en la orden, debería añadir whipCreamTopping verdadero.
And it does, except again, I forgot the new line character, so
Y lo hace, excepto porque olvidé el carácter de la nueva línea
I need to modify that now.
así que necesito modificar eso ahora.
Well since I'm here I should just check the other case.
Ya que estoy aquí debería comprobar el otro caso.
So I'm going to uncheck this box and hit the order button.
Desmarco esta casilla y presiono "ordenar".
And it says false.
Y dice "falso".
So it's correctly reflecting the state of the checked box.
Así que refleja correctamente el estado de la casilla marcada.
Now let's add the new line character and run the app again.
Ahora añadamos el carácter de la nueva línea y ejecutemos la app.
if I click the check box and then hit the order button then it's says true.
Si marco la casilla y luego presiono "ordenar", dice "verdadero".
If I uncheck it then click on order, it says false.
Si desmarco y presiono ordenar, dice "falso".
Awesome.
Genial.
That handles both cases.
Controla ambos casos.
The later parts of this task were easier.
La parte final de estas tareas ha sido más fácil.
Because once we verified in the logs that we were getting the right check
Porque una vez verificado en el registro que obtuvimos el
state, it was only a matter of showing on the screen.
estado correcto, es sólo cuestión de reflejarlo en la pantalla.
Since things are working inside the app now,
Ya que todo funciona dentro de la app
I can remove the log message because it's not needed anymore.
puedo quitar el mensaje de registro porque ya no lo necesito.
And then run the app one final time.
Y ejecutar una última vez la app.
Okay, great work.
Estupendo, funciona.
Let's move on to the next task.
Pasemos a la siguiente tarea.